- [Instructor] State management refers to the management
and manipulation of data within a web application.
It is the process for managing the data
in your React application with the implementation
of a design pattern to synchronize the state
throughout all the components of the application.
In a typical React application,
the data is stored in a state object.
The state object represents the state
of the application at any given time.
The way it works is that the view subscribes
to the state object.
Whenever the view receives an interaction,
and action is dispatched.
Then the view updates the user interface
on every state changes, and you can have multiple views
that share the same state updates.
Whenever there is a change in the state object,
the state updates are shared and synchronized
across all the components of the application.
Implementing state management is not an easy process though.
It requires time, lots of thinking, planning,
and maintenance.
So finding the right state management solution
is a great deal for any development team
to guarantee the success of your web projects.
So which solution should I pick?
As a React developer,
your role is not to pick a solution blindly,
or to stick to one choice
even if you are an unconditional fan.
You will need to think about which solution is best
for your needs.
Back in 2015, at the time when designs
and architecture like Flux had become trendy,
Dan Abramov once shared that "It is in React's spirit
to constantly question the dogma.
And we must be careful
not to introduce a dogma of our own.
As a community, we need to teach the beginners
to keep their eyes wide open
so they can recognize when something better
than Flux comes along."
So there is no need to implement state management
by following one design pattern only.
For example, while you've heard great benefits
about the Redux Library,
your small application might not need Redux.
Don't get me wrong, though.
Redux is by far a great library,
generally preferred for managing the state
in large web applications handling lots of data.
It is just that Redux is known
for requiring lots of boilerplate code,
you need to add and create actions.
It also introduces lots of complexity into your projects
and it is good to note as well
that the learning curve is not simple.
Lucky for us developers, the React ecosystem is very rich.
The great benefits is that React is highly flexible
and can be used everywhere.
Some popular state management solutions
includes the React API with useState and useReducer.
So no need to write a class anymore.
The state can be managed within functional components
that can hold and maintain their own states,
thanks to the hooks which have been in the React library
since 2018.
Another built-in feature of the React API is the Context API
that provides a way to create a global state
and a single source of truth.
In this course, we're going to see a few examples
with the Context API.
Then you have Redux,
which is a popular state management library
for the React applications.
Redux provides a centralized store for an easy managements
of complex states across multiple components.
Then you have other solutions like MobX
that works with reactive programming
and Vuex for view applications.
And you have the new kids on the block,
Recoil and Zustand.
Lightweight with anatomic approach,
both are designed to be simple, flexible
and easy to use
with a syntax very similar to React without the complexity
of traditional state management libraries.
And they both provide a simple way to manage the state
without the need for complex patterns or libraries.
Overall, effective state management leads
to easy data sharing and communication,
easy software testing and debugging,
and a better performance in optimization.
And the benefits are visible both from a technical
and a business perspective with a register development time
and cost, with an improved cut organization,
a better reusability and scalability.